I love making art and looking at artworks.
我热爱创作艺术，也喜欢欣赏艺术作品。
I’ve found myself wondering how we gain pleasure from art.
我发现自己一直在思考：我们是如何从艺术中获得愉悦的？
And now neuroaesthetics, a combination of neuroscience and aesthetics, may provide an answer.
而如今，结合了神经科学与美学的神经美学，或许能给出答案。
Neuroaesthetics is a relatively young field of research on what happens in the brain when we make aesthetic assessments.
神经美学是一个相对年轻的研究领域，研究的是我们进行审美评判时大脑中发生了什么。
Researchers use brain imaging techniques to see which brain areas light up when we view paintings that we consider beautiful.
研究人员借助脑成像技术，观察我们观看自己认为美的画作时，大脑的哪些区域会亮起来。
Similar research has been done to understand the “neuronal fireworks” that occur when we look at inspiring sculptures, attractive faces, impressive dance, etc.
为了弄清我们观看鼓舞人心的雕塑、迷人的面孔、令人赞叹的舞蹈等时出现的“神经元烟花”，人们也开展了类似的研究。
But why do we find some art beautiful and other art ugly?
但是，为什么我们会觉得有些艺术美、有些艺术丑呢？
According to research, it all comes down to the “aesthetic triad”.
据研究，这一切都归结于“审美三元组合”。
The first part of the triad is sensory-motor.
三元组合的第一部分是感觉—运动。
This involves perceiving things like colours, shapes and movements.
这涉及对颜色、形状和动作等事物的感知。
Movement in art has an interesting role.
艺术中的动作所起的作用很有意思。
If you see a painting of a movement, like of a man pulling his arm away after being bitten by a dog, you feel as if you are going through a similar experience.
如果你看到一幅描绘动作的画，比如一个男人被狗咬后把手臂缩回去，你会感觉自己仿佛也在经历类似的体验。
The part of your brain that controls your own movements lights up in response.
你大脑中控制自身动作的那部分会随之亮起来。
Second is emotion-valuation.
第二部分是情绪—评价。
This is how a piece of art makes you feel, and whether or not you appreciate or enjoy that feeling.
这指的是一件艺术作品给你带来怎样的感受，以及你是否欣赏或享受那种感受。
The part of the brain related to pleasure is activated in response to something we find beautiful.
一遇到我们觉得美的事物，大脑中与愉悦相关的部分就会被激活。
This system can be affected in fascinating ways, as found by research using transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS).
使用经颅磁刺激（TMS）的研究发现，这一系统可能会受到一些奇妙的影响。
If TMS is applied to a specific part of your brain behind your forehead that is particularly important for decision-making, you suddenly like different kinds of art.
如果对你前额后方一个对决策尤为重要的特定大脑区域施加TMS，你喜欢的艺术类型会突然改变。
Such stimulation produces significant changes in aesthetic appreciation of faces, bodies and artworks.
这种刺激会使人们对面孔、身体和艺术作品的审美欣赏发生显著变化。
The third part is meaning-knowledge.
第三部分是意义—知识。
This is to do with how we can connect with a piece of art and what meaning we can create in it.
这关系到我们如何与一件艺术作品建立联系，以及我们能在其中创造出什么意义。
Art is deeply personal, because when two people see the same artwork, their perceptions can create vastly different experiences of meaning.
艺术极具个人色彩，因为两个人看同一件艺术作品时，他们各自的感知可能带来截然不同的意义体验。
If we find meaning, then we often find pleasure.
如果我们找到了意义，往往也就能获得愉悦。
We also get enjoyment from the knowledge of how something was made.
了解某样东西是如何制作出来的，也会给我们带来乐趣。
For the images that an artist creates, viewers will probably get far more enjoyment once they know the process used to create them.
就艺术家创作的画面而言，观众一旦了解了创作这些画面的过程，很可能会获得多得多的乐趣。
Informed by neuroaesthetics, the next time I create my art I will value the process even more, enjoying the activation of the aesthetic triad in my brain as I admire the vivid images that I have created.
了解了神经美学之后，下次进行艺术创作时，我会更加珍视创作过程，一边欣赏自己创作出的生动画面，一边享受大脑中审美三元组合被激活的感觉。